<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Daniel Chipping</title>
    <link>https://dchipping.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Daniel Chipping</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <copyright>© Copyright notice</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dchipping.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Rendering real-time physics: video game physics engines</title>
      <link>https://dchipping.github.io/posts/physics-engines/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dchipping.github.io/posts/physics-engines/</guid>
      <description>Augmented reality in action &amp;ndash; a fast, portable and realistic physics engine is needed to calculate the collisions with complex surfaces in the real world (Lightship SDK)
  Curiosity has recently led me down the road of extended reality (XR), a catch-all term encompassing: Augmented Reality (AR), Mixed Reality (MR) and Virtual Reality (VR). Development of XR experiences interestingly uses much of the same tooling used to create video games, often using game engines like Unity to build and leverage technology in order to create virtual environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Basics of Rocket Engine Plumbing</title>
      <link>https://dchipping.github.io/posts/rockets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dchipping.github.io/posts/rockets/</guid>
      <description>An &amp;lsquo;artistic&amp;rsquo; rendition of engine cycles
  As I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading more about software design patterns, I recalled a bit of reading I did during university on rocket engines cycles and how the topic could be thought of in similar terms to a design pattern. The concept of a program&amp;rsquo;s pattern referring to a well recognised way of solving a particular problem. Businesses typically like to implement them in their software designs due to the benefits:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
